<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="000style.xsl"?>
<teiCorpus>
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Digitised and Encoded copy of Negro Slavery by Zachary MacAulay</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Transcribed from digital copy available from Recovered Histories at
                    http://www.recoveredhistories.org/pamphlet1.php?page=1&amp;orderby=MaxID&amp;catid=66</authority>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
                        <title>Negro Slavery; or, A View of Some of the More Prominent Features of
                            that State of Society, as it Exists in the United States of America and
                            in the Colonies of the West Indies, Especially in Jamaica</title>
                    </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Printed for Hatchard and Son, Piccadilly, and J. and A. Arch,
                            Cornhill</publisher>
                        <distributor>Sold Also by W. Graphel, Church street, and G. and J. Robison,
                            Castle Street, Liverpool.</distributor>
                        <date when="1823">1823</date>
                        <pubPlace>
                            <settlement>London</settlement>
                        </pubPlace>
                    </publicationStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <TEI>
        <teiHeader>
            <fileDesc>
                <titleStmt>
                    <title/>
                </titleStmt>
                <publicationStmt>
                    <authority>Transcribed by a student of Digital History at Sheffield Hallam
                        University</authority>
                </publicationStmt>
                <sourceDesc>
                    <bibl>
                        <biblScope>101</biblScope>
                    </bibl>
                </sourceDesc>
            </fileDesc>
        </teiHeader>
        <text>
            <body>
              <p>dential communications were recorded, by the legislatures of <placeName key="Saint Vincent and the Grenadines" ref="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saint_Vincent_and_the_Grenadines">St. Vincent's</placeName> and of the <placeName key="?, Leeward Islands" ref="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leeward_Islands">Leeward Islands</placeName>, as the basis of their proceedings, and as such they made their appearance unexpectedly on the table of the House of Commons.</p>
              <p>In consequence of this correspondence, some, but not all, of the colonial legislatures were induced so far to yield a decent compliance with the roal requisition, as to pass what they called meliorating acts. These, however, have generally, we may say universally, proved a dead letter. The governor of <placeName key="Dominica" ref="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dominica">Dominica</placeName>, <persName key="Prevost, George" from="1767" to="1816" role="Govenor of Dominica" ref="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/George_Prévost">General Prevost</persName>, when called upon by the Secretary of State, <persName key="Pratt, John" from="1759" to="1840" role="Secretary of State for War and the Colonies" ref="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Pratt,_1st_Marquess_Camden">Earl Camden</persName>, in <persName key="Prevost, George" from="1767" to="1816" role="Govenor of Dominica" ref="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/George_Prévost">his</persName> circular letter of the 4th of October, 1804, to specify what had been their effect in that island, replied that "from the many years I have passed in the <placeName key="West Indies" ref="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/West_Indies">West Indies</placeName>, and as a resident in most of the colonies, I may venture to represent to <persName key="Pratt, John" from="1759" to="1840" role="Secretary of State for War and the Colonies" ref="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Pratt,_1st_Marquess_Camden">Your Lordship</persName> the legislature of <placeName key="?, Dominica" ref="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dominica">Dominica</placeName> as distinguised by the laws it has passed, for the encouragement, protection, and government of slaves; but, I am sorry I cannot add, that they are as religiously observed as you could wish." - As for "the act of the legislature, <interp key="Thomas Jefferson's reason for displacing blacks by whites was because he thought Negroes were an inferior race, the deep rooted prejudice by whites, and that the two races could never live in freedom and harmony together under the same government." n="Founders Online: 51. A Bill concerning Slaves, 18 June 1779. (n.d.). Retrieved from https://founders.archives.gov/documents/Jefferson/01-02-02-0132-0004-0051" cert="high" ref="https://founders.archives.gov/documents/Jefferson/01-02-02-0132-0004-0051">'An Act for the Encouragement, Protection, and better Government of Slaves</interp>,' it appears to have been considered, from the day it was passed, until this hour, as a political measure to avert the interference of the mother-country in the management of slaves. Having said this, <persName key="Pratt, John" from="1759" to="1840" role="Secretary of State for War and the Colonies" ref="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Pratt,_1st_Marquess_Camden">Your Lordship</persName> will not be surprised to learn that the seventh clause of that bill has been wholly neglected."</p>
              <p>In other cases the avowal of the motives was not so explicit, but in all the return was NIL.</p>
            </body>
        </text>
    </TEI>
</teiCorpus>
